-- Addic7ed.com --
Hello?
Must be Pink's room?
I need a bed.
What?!
Go, go, go! Go!
Well, I need a place to sit!
Oh! Oh, oh!
Hmm.
I need a shelf for my face,
face, face, face, face.
Eh.
Hey! Who the heck are
you little guys?
Thank you!
"Thank you"?
- Is it...
- It is her!
- Why does she look different?
- She's back!
It's time! It's time!
Oh, Diamond ... Pink, Pink!
Aagh!
Don't ... don't build
stuff in my mouth.
All right, who are you guys?
- Very funny, Pink!
- Always playing her games.
Pretending she doesn't
know us pebbles.
- Pearl!
- Steven!
Oh, thank the stars!
You're okay!
What did White Diamond do?
Did she hurt you?!
No, she was like,
"Welcome home."
I don't think she understands
that I'm not Pink Diamond.
Where's Connie?
And Garnet and Amethyst?
They're still on the ship.
I'm only here because
I'm bringing your things.
And they consider me
one of your things.
Yeesh.
The Diamond chime ...
it's Yellow!
Pink Diamond, my Diamond
has requested your presence
in the extraction chamber.
Let's get you into a suit.
Swim trunks don't
seem very formal.
Trust me, this will be
more comfortable than jeans.
Hello!
- Pink Diamond.
- Please, call me Steven.
- Pink Steven.
- No, just Steven.
Just Steven.
Call me...
lasagna.
Steven, stop, you're
going to break her.
Have a nice extraction,
Pink Lasagna.
- Pink.
- Hi, Yellow. Cool sauna.
It's new.
Have a seat.
Oop!
So, you met with White.
How was it?
All I got to say was,
"Hi," and, "um," and, "I."
Two and a half words ...
that's a record.
Two and a half words
isn't enough.
I still need to talk to White
about healing
- all the corrupted gems!
- Hmm. Good luck.
White never leaves
her own head these days,
and she never lets anyone in ...
except you, I guess.
It's so unfair.
I have hundreds of successful
crystal system colonies,
but you get to see her because
your one colony is a failure!
Maybe you should just...
fail?
Oh, Pink, you always
did have quite a knack
for making me laugh.
You're almost worth the trouble.
Ugh.
Already?
Excuse me.
I've got to check on the latest
Citrine production reports.
What should I do about White?
I still need to talk to her
about helping the corrupted gems.
Pink Diamond, my Diamond
has requested your presence.
We barely talked about White at all.
She had to rush to do a report,
and I couldn't go with her.
I get they're, like, busy,
'cause they're dictators
and everything
but I need more time!
I should have asked her
what she was doing
- after the Citron thing!
- She'll be at that for a while.
Yellow Diamond oversees
all aspects of gem production
on every single one
of her colonies.
And when she's not doing that,
she's off with her army,
conquering the next one.
What about their days off,
weekends?
My Diamond is
awaiting our arrival.
Blue Diamond is
just up the stairs.
- I'll wait for you here.
- I'll be back in a bit!
Welcome back.
♪ You'll never be alone-y ♪
♪ As long as
you are combing ♪
You're here! Come in!
Okay.
Whoo-hoo!
It's funny. I ... I live
right next to the ocean,
but I end up going
to space to swim.
You haven't changed.
So silly. So small.
I'm not done growing.
I'm not sure I can catch up
to you and Yellow, though.
I'm so glad you're back...
Steven.
- Y-you actually said my name!
- Steven.
Steee-von.
It's such a funny sounding name.
You're so creative, Pink!
Remember when
I let you name
that batch of pyrite
"fool's gold"?
White was furious!
I'm sorry.
I don't remember.
Oh. Do you remember the game
we used to play here?
We had such fun together ...
you and I and Yellow
and White.
We were all together here?!
You would stand under water,
all the way at the bottom,
and sing.
And we would be
above the surface
trying to guess the song.
Can we do that
right now?
Maybe after, we can talk White
into coming back to Earth with us.
No. We stopped coming here
together after you left.
That was the start of Era 2.
No one wanted to be here ...
not with your empty spot.
It was so quiet.
I know you guys have
colony stuff to do,
but we should spend
more time together.
My apologies, my Diamond,
but your next appointment.
- Of course.
- Wait!
I wanted to talk
to you about White.
- Later, perhaps.
- Aah!
- Pearl?
- Steven?
- Some water got up my nose.
- Oh, dear.
This is so weird.
Was this some sort of
spa day or something?
And what about Pink?
Did she have a job here,
or did she just
sit in her room
while they were off
doing whatever?
Before her colony, Pink used
to throw massive balls.
She was a juggler?!
No ... Well, yes.
But she would also throw parties
for the other Diamonds,
to mark their
many accomplishments.
Every member of every court
would show up to bask
in the presence
of all four Diamonds.
Even White would come?
Oh, yes!
Huh. I wonder what's even
become of Pink's court.
That reminds me.
Hang tight. I'll be back.
Where would I
even...go?
What did I get myself into?
Am I just supposed to
be Pink Diamond now?
Hey, pebbles, can you help me?
Who was she?
What did she do?
And why does this feel so...
- Oh.
- Ooh!
♪ Familiar ♪
♪ Why is this so familiar? ♪
♪ Like something
I used to know ♪
♪ Used to know ♪
♪ Familiar ♪
♪ Staring up at the ceiling ♪
♪ I swear that I know
this feeling ♪
♪ Where everybody
wants me to be Mom ♪
- ♪ Wants me to be Mom ♪
♪ And everything I do,
I do it wrong ♪
♪ I do, I do it wrong ♪
♪ I'll sway them with a joke
or with a song ♪
♪ Or with a song ♪
♪ And maybe that'll
help us get along ♪
♪ Familiar ♪
♪ Why is this so familiar? ♪
♪ Like something I used to do ♪
♪ Used to do ♪
♪ Familiar ♪
♪ Did she used to
throw a tantrum? ♪
♪ Insisting "But hey,
I'm a Diamond, too!" ♪
♪ I bet she drove them
crazy all the time ♪
♪ Crazy all the time ♪
♪ They love her, but they're
leaving her behind ♪
♪ With more important places
they should be ♪
♪ Places they should be ♪
♪ Than hanging out with
someone just like me ♪
♪ Familiar ♪
♪ That's why it's so familiar ♪
♪ That's why it's ♪
♪ Familiar ♪
♪ Like someone I used to be ♪
♪ Someone I used to be ♪
♪ Familiar ♪
♪ But this time,
I've had some practice ♪
♪ This time I've had ♪
♪ At helping
a struggling family ♪
♪ A struggling family ♪
♪ Oh, I'll get them
all together in one place ♪
♪ And once we're all
together face to face ♪
♪ I'll show them all
the error of their ways ♪
♪ And end their spread
of terror across space ♪
Steven!
I'm back with ...
Hi, Pearl.
I just thought I'd, uh,
dress for the occasion.
Well...
you're not the only one
with surprises.
Guys!
Mmm!
I figured it out!
Remember back when I was little
and maybe kind of annoying,
and I couldn't come
along on adventures?
You guys would still drop
everything to hang out with me!
That's Pink Diamond!
I know I can do this!
Just watch ... I'm gonna
throw a huge ball,
and I'm gonna invite everyone!
♪ Look at you go ♪
♪ I just adore you ♪
♪ I wish that I knew ♪
♪ What makes you think
I'm so special? ♪
-- Addic7ed.com --