♪ We ♪
♪ Are the Crystal Gems ♪
♪ We'll always save the day ♪
♪ And if you think we can't ♪
♪ We'll always find a way ♪
♪ That's why the people ♪
♪ Of this world ♪
♪ Believe in ♪
- ♪ Garnet ♪
- ♪ Amethyst ♪
♪ And Pearl ♪
And Steven!
*STEVEN UNIVERSE*
Season 05  Episode 28
Episode Title: "Change Your Mind"
Sync corrections  by  srjanapala
Oh, right... prison.
I cannot
believe you.
Making a scene
like that.
We weren't trying
to make a scene!
We were just...
dancing...?
Connie?
What have you
done with Connie?
What have I done?
What have you done?
You're the one that wanted
to keep those organics
from the Kyanite colony.
I'm just the fool
that let you.
What?
Now your little pets
are chasing
the pearls up
and down the halls.
What were you thinking...
Letting them loose
in the ballroom?
They could be anywhere.
- Bah!
- Ah! Eee!
Pink!
Ugh. Please.
Just get rid of it.
Pink...
White is very unhappy
with you.
If this keeps up, she's going
to take away your pearl.
I know.
I'm sorry.
Huh?
Why do you always do this,
Pink?
Huh?
Huh?!
No, stop!
Oh, Connie,
you... you're here.
Yeah.
Can't exactly leave...
I cannot believe you...
Making a scene like that.
Whoa... deja blue.
We didn't mean any harm.
I asked Steven to dance.
He wasn't trying
to cause trouble.
What do you know
about this, human?
You think I've never
been grounded before?
"Grounded"?
Blue, you gotta
let us out of here.
We're gonna starve.
"Starve"?
What is this?
Another made up problem?
Another trick,
so I'll cave and let you out?
Well, not this time.
You're
not leaving this tower
until you apologize
for fusing at the ball.
No.
- Steven.
- What? I'm not sorry.
We finally
have you back...
and you're worse
than ever.
Steven!
It's fine, Connie.
I'm not even sad.
But you're
really dehydrated!
Blue, Connie and I
fuse all the time.
It's totally
normal and fine.
Agh! In what universe
could that possibly be fine?
This universe!
The crystal gems fuse
all the time, too.
Blue, you gotta tell me
where their gems are.
They didn't do
anything wrong.
Oh! Pink!
Your time on Earth has warped
your sense of right and wrong.
Yeah, maybe it has.
Maybe Pink thought you guys
were right to lock her
in here when
she messed stuff up.
But I know what it's like
to have a loving family,
and we don't do stuff
like this to each other.
The crystal gems understand
that I'm Steven,
and they support me
and Connie.
And you guys poofed 'em
for sticking up for me.
That isn't normal.
That's enough!
This isn't normal.
How many times did you
lock her in here?
How many times
did you make her cry?
I didn't, I...
And I'm doing it again,
aren't I?
And this is why you left,
isn't it?
You were right to leave.
I always thought that
you were failing this world.
But if you were
happier on Earth,
maybe this world
was failing you.
We never should have
brought you back here!
Your "family,"
your "crystal gems" are bubbled.
Let's get you all
back in your legs...
and back home.
All right, it's safe.
Food!
Good-bye, Pebbles.
Wish us luck.
I'm ready.
We've got friends to save.
What... are you doing?
I'm taking back my friends!
What are you doing, Blue?
Take Pink
back to the tower.
She prefers to be
called "Steven."
What are you
talking about?!
You can't keep bending
the rules for her, Blue.
She has to set an example.
And we have to set an example.
If we bend the rules for her,
we bend them for everyone.
Well,
maybe you should.
Take them back
to the tower, now!
I won't.
Then I'll do it myself.
Blue?!
Ugh!
Steven, now.
When we thought
Pink was shattered,
when she abandoned us,
I alone was there for you.
And you would use
your power against me?!
They're free.
Come on, guys.
You're not bubbled anymore.
You can come out.
Are they okay?
You'd hurt
a fellow diamond?!
Didn't we hurt Pink?
She was suffering
in silence for ages...
Just like our gems,
just like me!
And I know you're
suffering in silence, too.
Stop!
You don't have to do this.
Yes, I do.
This is what White Diamond
expects of all of us...
From a thin flake of mica
to the deepest, hardest stone...
We all must make sacrifices for
the sake of our perfect empire.
Does this look
perfect to you?
My dad says if every
pork chop were perfect,
we wouldn't
have hot dogs.
And that means what?
It means if you try to make
this empire perfect,
if you just wipe away
everything you see as flawed...
you lose all the things
that make you happy...
Like hot dogs.
Or our Pink.
Uh...
Stop.
Stop it, Blue.
Stop using
your power on me.
I'm not!
Steven, come on.
Grab the gems.
Let's get out of here.
Right.
I hope they're okay.
Amethyst would usually
be back by now.
They'll be out
for a good while.
They took
a direct hit from me.
Yellow, we've got to
get them out of here...
before White finds out
about any of this.
Right. Quickly.
Your legs are this way.
Don't worry, guys.
I'll get you home safe.
Even if we have
to escape now,
we'll find some way to heal
the corrupted gems.
We can come back to Homeworld.
W-we'll still have the legs.
I don't know. I don't know
if White will ever see us.
We're almost there.
Here we are.
Hurry, get inside.
You're not going anywhere.
You've made a grave mistake.
Go to your rooms!
Uh...
Which rooms should we go to?
Blue, don't make her any
angrier than she already is.
We're busted.
Looks like this just
turned into a face-off.
Amethyst, Pearl, Garnet?
Please... I think
we're really in trouble.
What the heck is that?!
Yellow, Blue... did you
have a hand in this?
No way.
White, that wasn't us!
We swear!
Then who's that?
Who cares!
Knock her out!
Who's responsible
for this?
Gasp.
I always wanted to uppercut
an upper crust!
Bismuth!
You came!
Heck yeah, we did.
We?
Of course.
You thought we wouldn't
be here at a time like this?
Lapis Lazuli
and Peridot!
That felt great.
Wasn't that cool, Steven?
Check out the awesome job we did
fixing up those hand ships.
Uh... who needs thumbs?
Very cute.
Glad to see
we're having fun.
However, White Diamond has
certain issues with your conduct
that will need to be addressed
before we move forward.
Steven, quickly... use one
of our ships to get home.
- Huh?
- Yes.
You have another chance.
Take my arm.
Fly to Earth.
Yellow and I will keep
White distracted.
Blue, Yellow...
Don't worry, Steven.
We understand now.
This way of living...
it must've been like
torture for you.
Just go! Hurry!
She's getting up!
No. No, I won't go.
Pink Diamond
ran away from you.
Rose Quartz, my mom,
she started a war with you.
But I don't want to run.
I don't want to fight.
I just want to talk.
We've come so far just to get
White Diamond's attention,
and now we finally
have it.
If we can fix our family,
we can fix everything!
But in order to fix it,
we'd have to admit
that it's broken.
She'll never
want to hear it.
But it's the truth!
My mom back on Earth
used to have
so many rules
for me to follow.
It was so overwhelming,
and it made me feel miserable.
After I told her
how I was feeling,
things got way
better between us.
She even let me come out
to space to help Steven.
If White knew how unhappy
she's made you feel,
maybe everything
would change.
What do you say, Yellow?
Do you think White
might actually
listen to us
for a change?
It's worth a try.
Lend me a hand,
will you, Blue?
Okay.
- Huh?
- The ships!
Steven, take a knee.
Okay.
White, please.
All we want
you to do is listen!
That's it, Steven.
Come on, Blue.
That's it.
Come on, everybody.
Hey, White, I know I was
in there with you for a second,
but I barely got
to talk to you at all.
There are so many gems
that are hurting right now.
Even Blue and Yellow
are hurting!
You should hear
what they have to say!
Mmm.
This is it!
We...
We... we...
We need to talk!
About us.
I've conquered so many worlds
for the sake of the empire.
I do everything you ask,
and I do it all perfectly.
But your very high standards put
us all under a lot of pressure.
A Gem could crack
under so much pressure.
We Diamonds may be hard,
but we're also brittle.
White,
we used to be close.
Don't you remember?
♪ When Pink
would make us laugh ♪
All those silly things
she did for no reason.
There was a reason.
She wanted us
to be happy together.
But we weren't,
and we're still not.
I know my purpose
isn't to be happy,
but I find it harder
and harder
to enforce your rules
when they make me
miserable.
When they make
us all miserable.
White, please,
why don't you let us all
into your head?
We could come up with
a plan to help everyone.
You could start
by helping Yellow and Blue.
Aaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaah!
Aaaaaaah!
What?!
Guys?!
Ah!
We gotta go!
- Whah-aah!
- Aaaaah!
Peridot, over there!
Steven!
Grab on!
- No!
- Steven!
Ah!
Amethyst!
Please reform.
I need you.
Amethyst, can you
hear me in there?
Everyone's falling!
We can save them.
Together!
Don't worry.
I'm here for...
Uh...
What just happened?
Mmm...
Holy smokes!
I'm smoky!
Steven, you beautiful genius.
You pulled Amethyst
out of her Gem through fusion?
Pearl!
Gotta throw Steven...
Don't worry about me.
"Owl" be fine.
Come on, Pearl, dance with me.
Well, what do you know?
It's Rainbow 2.0.
Now, this is
a fine mess we're in. Huh!
That won't do.
Pbbbbbt!
Rainbow Quartz powers,
activate!
Ah, yes.
Now that's two stones
with one bird.
Wow!
Nice form, Pearl.
Oh, thank you.
I'm particularly excited
about the jacket.
Aah!
Steven! We fused!
Are you guys okay?
Almost. Garnet, we're up
against a giant robot.
We need your help.
Please come out.
I'm here!
I love you!
♪ Awwwwwwwwwww ♪
♪ Yeah! ♪
You better step off!
Chillax, my dudes.
Your rockin' pal Sunstone
is holdin' it down.
Wow!
- Holy...
- All right!
Unbelievable!
Oh, you better believe it.
Okay!
Sunstone,
what are we gonna do?
White Diamond's
never going to listen
and she's never
going to let us leave.
If she won't listen,
we'll make her listen.
And how are we
gonna do that?
I know she's in there.
We'll bust into her head
and change her mind.
Right!
Let's take that bully down!
But remember, kids:
If you ever have to deal
with a bully,
be sure to tell an adult.
Oh!
Come on!
Ally-oop!
Kids, don't try this at home.
Ha!
Bungakowa!
Ah! Yeah!
You can do it!
Believe in yourself!
Always. do.
Your best!
Oh, no!
Wah! Owwwwwww!
Oof!
Agh! Ahh!
No dice.
We need to be bigger.
Then let's fuse.
All four of us.
It's the only way we're
gonna get up to her head.
- I'm in!
- I'm in, too.
Then it's decided.
It's time to form Obsidian.
Huh?
Whoa!
Aaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaah!
They're hu-u-u-u-ge!
Hunh!
Uah!
Guys, we've gotta
do something
to keep those hands
off of them.
Right. But, first,
I made you
a little somethin'.
My own sword?
It's perfect!
Let's show White Diamond
we mean Bismuth.
Grab on.
Time to take
this thing apart!
Set your eyes on me,
Homeworld!
I, Peridot, have returned,
not as your servant,
but as your savior!
I rule the skies!
Roh! Wh-wh-whoa!
Try and catch me,
you enlarged,
bipedal housing unit!
Whoa! Ah!
Lapis! Bismuth!
Ahhgh!
Aah-aah-aah!
Hold on! I've got ya!
Whoa-whoa-oa-oa-oa-oa!
Whoa-whoa-oa-oa!
Ooh.
Oof!
Ah.
Aah!
Whoa-ah!
Aaaaah!
Ah. Ohh. Uhhhhh.
Whoa-oa-oa-aah-aah-aah!
Ah!
Ah! Thanks.
Heads up! I've got this!
Ahh-aah!
I'll let you take this one.
Anh!
Guys! Connie!
Keep going!
I'm right behind you!
There!
We can get inside
through the eye.
Come on!
Hurry!
Whoa-ah!
Huh!
White Diamond.
Oh, Starlight,
what are you doing,
crawling in here?
You want your legs back?
You want
your planet back?
Surely, you can understand
why I can't let you leave.
Look what you did
to yourself last time.
White Diamond, my name
is Steven Universe.
I'm here to...
Aah!
My, my.
We've been causing
quite a scene, haven't we?
What have you done
to them?! They're...
Shhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhh!
Poor Yellow.
Her impurities absorb
all the blue in her light.
She's so strong...
but so weak,
when it comes to Blue.
Ah, and Blue...
Her impurities soak up all
of the warmth in her spectrum.
She thinks she needs you, Pink.
As for me, I'm certain
I don't need you.
After all, I'm every
color of the light.
But you're a part of me.
The part I always
have to repress.
What?!
Dude, what is she
even talking about?
This is nonsense!
Oh. Hello there.
Your new friends are so funny.
Is that what they're
supposed to be, funny?
Aaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaah!
Hey, White dirtwad!
That all you got?!
Huh?
Oh, no!
Leave her alone!
Aggggggh!
Arrrrrrrggggggghhhhhhh!
Stop!
Ah! Ahh!
Ahh ahh ahhhh!
Ahhhhh!
It's a pity, the way
you bring out the worst in others.
See how you've encouraged
their deficiencies?
It's written all
over their Gems:
insecure,
dependent,
obsessed.
Oh, no, no.
Guys!
Come on,
snap out of it!
Please stop helping them.
You'll only make things worse.
That's what you do.
I make things better.
Here...
Oh, thank you,
White Diamond.
I feel excellent now.
Oh, thank you.
How generous of you.
Thank you, White Diamond.
We feel so much better now.
I feel excellent.
There we are!
I've removed their flaws.
Now, there is nothing
to hinder my white light
from sparkling through them.
I'd rather not spread
my uninhibited self so thin,
you know, but you've made it
absolutely necessary.
Now, the impurities you've
encouraged in them are gone.
Now, they are brilliant!
Now, they are perfect!
Now...
they are me!
You're wrong.
Please,
just listen to me!
My friends don't need
to be fixed!
They're fine the way they
are, flaws and all!
There you go again.
Do you understand
why you defend their flaws?
I know why, Pink.
You like surrounding yourself
with inferior Gems.
What?!
You enable
their terrible behavior,
so you can be
the best of the worst.
That's not true!
And, even if it is...
Even if it was,
y-you're talking
about my mom.
You're not talking
about me!
Your "mom"?
Guys, I'm here!
Huh?
Pearl?
Connie!
Well, what have we here?
It's another one of your pets.
Wait! Whoa!
Huh?
Aah!
Let her go.
These worthless Gems
weren't enough, were they?
See how you surround yourself
with lower life forms?
You've smothered
yourself in them.
It feels good, doesn't it, Pink?
Dulling your power,
hiding your face,
blaming everything
on someone else.
You became Rose Quartz
to deceive
your pathetic friends.
And, now,
you've improved on that,
because you're even
deceiving yourself.
No. You're wrong!
I'm not my mom!
But don't you know things
about her
that you couldn't possibly know?
I-I've just been
connecting with her.
My powers, they...
They help me
connect to others.
I-I'm not her.
I'm just...
feeling her feelings.
Isn't it obvious?
Even though you've embedded
yourself in that human child,
your light can't help
shining through.
You know you're in there.
You've known it all along.
Stop cowering inside your Gem.
You can hide from yourself,
but you can't hide
from me, Pink.
Don't listen to her,
Steven!
She's just trying
to mess with you!
Steven!
Now, Starlight,
this has gone on long enough.
It's time to come out,
Pink.
No-o-o-o-o!
Steven.
Steven, please.
Steven, wake up.
Look at me! Please.
Steven?
Steven!
What?
No. Where?
Where... Where's my...?
Anh!
Steven!
No.
Please, I...
I need... I need...
What is this?
Where is Pink?
She's gone.
What did you say?
Answer me!
She's go-o-o-o-o-o-o-ne!
Where do you think
you're going?
Help.
Steven!
Hold on!
Don't you dare take
one more step!
One more step!
That's enough!
Ahhh, you little...
Agh! Don't you raise
your shield at me!
I only want you
to be yourself!
If you can't do that,
I'll do it
for! you!
Aaaah!
No, stop.
You're hurting them!
Ahh!
Here.
What are you doing?
Pink!
Why are you laughing?
Steven!
Oh!
Are you back together?
Are you you?
Yeah! Yeah, I'm me!
I've always been me...
No! You are Pink Diamond!
That is Pink Diamond's gem!
You do not look like this!
You do not sound like this!
You are not half human,
you're just...
acting like a child!
I am a child.
What's your excuse?
What's happening?
What is this?
What's wrong with them?
They're turning pink!
I don't understand...
I'm in control, I...
Something's wrong...
with me!
No!
- Guys!
Steven...
Are you okay?!
Uh, what happened?
I think Steven got
through to her!
Aah!
- Aah!
- Ha!
Listen up, you nail heads!
The Crystal Gems
are here to... huh?
Steven!
Are you okay?
Are you hurt?
Oh, look at White.
She's shakin' like
a piece of chalk!
Wh-What happened...
Where am I?
Welcome back.
What is this?!
I feel... ridiculous.
Yellow, Blue!
She's off-color.
This can't be happening!
I can't have a flaw!
I'm supposed to be flawless!
If I'm not perfect,
then... who am I?!
If you're not Pink,
then... who are you?!
Who... Who is anyone?!
Ya know, if you just let
everyone be whoever they are,
maybe you could let yourself
be whoever you are, too.
But I'm not supposed
to be like this!
I'm supposed to know better!
I'm supposed to be better!
I'm supposed to make
everything better!
You can!
But first, you're going to
have to leave your own head.
♪ And if we look at a place ♪
♪ Well, baby, that's okay ♪
♪ I'll drive us
into outer space ♪
♪ Where we can't hear
what people say ♪
♪ I know I don't have a plan ♪
♪ I'm workin' on that part ♪
♪ At least I've got a van ♪
♪ So let me drive my van
into your heat ♪
♪ Let me drive my van
into your heart ♪
Steven!
Dad!
Oof!
Welcome home!
Huh?
I predict our long journey
through space will soon be over.
Lars: Welcome home, guys.
We finally made it!
Earth!
No more running,
no more hiding!
No more
Diamond Authority!
Welp...
we're cracked.
Wait, wait! It's okay!
I know what you're thinking,
but they're here to help!
Off colors,
meet the Diamonds.
Diamonds,
meet the off colors!
Hello.
Aah! It's the Diamonds!
Padparadscha,
it's okay!
Hey, Lars,
remember Lion?
Hey there, buddy.
Whoa!
Lars?
It's really you!
Sadie?!
There she is!
It's her!
We're about to see
Sadie... in person!
Hey.
Lars isn't going
to know what to say!
Shh!
Give 'em a moment!
Lars... look at you!
You're...
You're a space pirate!
Look at you!
You're a rock star!
Well...
I think it suits us!
Yeah. Me, too!
Ah!
Oh, I gotta get back on stage!
Oh, no! I totally
crashed your show!
You wish!
That honor goes to Steven.
Sorry, Sadie!
I'll make it up to you!
Hey, that's
not a bad idea!
Hey, Beach City,
we're not done yet!
I'd like to welcome my friend
and yours to the stage...
Steven Universe!
Thanks, Sadie!
♪ We ♪
♪ Are the Crystal Gems ♪
♪ We'll always save the day ♪
♪ And if you think we can't ♪
♪ We'll always find a way ♪
♪ That's why the people
of this world ♪
♪ Believe in ♪
♪ Garnet, Amethyst, and Pearl ♪
♪ And ♪
♪ If you're staring
with your giant eyes ♪
♪ You can see that there's
more of us than four of us ♪
♪ And each one of our
new friends completes us ♪
♪ We'll get together
and go out for pizzas ♪
♪ 'Cause we believe in peace ♪
♪ And love ♪
♪ We are here for fun ♪
♪ If you're not ♪
♪ Then let's not fight ♪
♪ 'Cause we've ♪
♪ Already won ♪
Room for three more?
Always.
- Whatcha playing?
- I had an idea.
Well, a song idea...
But also an idea idea.
Let's hear it.
- Yeah!
- Yes, please!
♪ I don't need you
to respect me, I respect me ♪
♪ I don't need you to love me,
I love me ♪
♪ But I want you to know
you could know me ♪
♪ If you change your mind ♪
♪ Change your mind ♪
♪ You ♪