- Addic7ed.com -
I know my mom
did something really bad.
Whatever Homeworld
has in store for me...
I'm ready!
I said, I'm ready!
It's me ... Rose Quartz!
Hello?
Anybody?
Lars, are you there?
Is this the punishment?
Come on!
I know it's going to be
worse than this!
So whatever you're gonna do...
would you just do it already?
This is ridiculous!
4,000 years of loyal
service to the court,
and this is what I get?
Oh, I'm the unluckiest Zircon
in the galaxy!
Wait, are you...
- Rose Quartz?
- Yeah.
- Really?
- It's a long story.
Then I don't have time for it.
Ugh!
We only have this brief
moment to prepare your case.
- Case?
- Ugh! Who am I kidding?!
This is pointless!
We've all heard the rumors
about the demise
of Pink Diamond,
but I can't believe these files!
Shattered by one
of her own soldiers ... ha!
In front of her entire entourage!
And look at you now!
That ridiculous disguise
is only going to make you
- look more guilty!
- That's fine, because I am!
Well, don't say that ...
especially not when
you're out there!
Out where?!
What's going to happen!?
What did you think was
going to happen, Rose Quartz?!
As soon as that door opens,
you're going on trial!
Oh.
Defending a rebel?
Isn't that ... treason?
I was assigned to this!
All rise for the luminous
Yellow Diamond!
And the lustrous Blue Diamond.
Where is the accused?
Is that Rose Quartz?
Look at this hideous form
she's taken.
Forget the trial.
We should shatter her
just for looking like that.
No! I want to hear her
make her case.
I want to know what she thinks
we're going to do with her,
because I want to
do something worse.
Fine! Let's just get on
with it, shall we?
My Diamond.
My brilliant, opulent,
radiant, glimmering ...
"My Diamond" will suffice,
or we'll never get through this.
Of course, My Diamond.
Rose Quartz committed
a crime so unprecedented
that one can't help
but wonder ... why?
Exhibit "A."
- Lars!
- Steven! What's going on here?!
Where are we?!
Who are those huge, giant ladies?!
As we can see from this specimen...
...humans are loud,
absolutely hideous creatures
that serve no purpose whatsoever.
What sort of Gem would turn on
her own kind for this?
I'll tell you what kind ...
that kind.
Just let him go! He's got
nothing to do with this!
There it is ...
the passion, the fury ...
that caused the diabolical
Rose Quartz to...
shatter her own diamond!
But I know what
you're thinking...
"This thing doesn't look like
a Rose Quartz."
And for that, I would like
to call an eyewitness!
Oh, Eyeball!
Do not address me,
war criminal!
I'm just glad you're okay.
I heard it straight from her.
She said...
"I'm the mighty Rose Quartz.
I've got her shield
and everything."
And then she threw me
into space!
I tried to help you!
I healed your Gem!
And who else has the ability
to heal Gems other than
the villainous...
Rose Quartz?!
And there you have it!
Rose Quartz did it,
and that's Rose Quartz.
I rest my case.
Oh, she's good.
Well, I'm convinced!
Time to execute!
Not yet. The defense
still has to speak.
Right! Well, uh...
Before I start, my very,
uh, thought-out defense,
I'd like to remind the court
that Rose Quartz
did turn herself in.
The Court remembers,
and the Court does not care.
Uh, of course.
Uh, in ... innocent!
Uh, the word "innocent"
can mean,
- oh, many different things.
- I did it!
Wha... What, what!
Stop!
No! I want to hear
what she has to say.
Get us out of here, Steven!
Uh...
State your name for
the record, please!
I, um...
I am Rose Quartz...
and I'm guilty.
Wait! No, don't say that!
Everything you guys
said I did, I did.
And I did it by myself.
I'm sorry.
I'll accept any punishment
you want to give me.
Just let him go!
And leave the Earth alone.
Ha! Sounds like
a solid confession to me!
How?
How did you do it?
Huh?
How did you shatter
Pink Diamond?
Um, well...
I did it on Earth in front
of Pink Diamond's palanquin.
I was probably like "Stop!"
And she was all like, "No!"
So we fought ... I think.
And she probably did
some cool moves.
I probably did
some cool stuff, too,
some jump kicks and stuff.
But I was most likely
deeply conflicted
about deciding to shatter her.
Definitely crying.
I probably had to use
the Breaking Point to do it.
It was a sword!
You ... shattered her...
with a sword!
That's quite enough
testimony from you!
We shall take
a short recess.
What are you saying in there?!
"Maybe" this,
"probably" that!
Oh, what do you mean
probably?!
Look, I just...
I don't actually know
how it happened, okay?
You don't know?!
- I...
- Don't tumble my rocks!
Both our Gems are on the line!
- Did you do this or not?!
- It was me, all right!
Rose Quartz did it,
and I've got her Gem,
so I'm the one
who's gotta pay for this!
You don't know how
it happened.
I get it.
There's a reason
they want you to explain
how you did it.
Huh?
It's because it
doesn't make sense!
Rose Quartz is flawed,
I grant you.
A shallow strata Gem
who turned on her own kind
out of a misguided
attachment to a planet
and creatures like these.
What?! Huh?!
It's indisputable that as
the diamond overseeing Earth,
Pink was Rose Quartz's enemy.
Rose had everything to gain
by shattering her.
But even though she may
have wanted to shatter
Pink Diamond, could she?
Blue Diamond, for the purpose
of this argument,
may I present
your palanquin?
Is this necessary?
Isn't it?
Please, proceed.
Now, as the records show,
Pink Diamond was shattered
just outside a palanquin
much like this.
Witnesses said,
Pink had stepped out
and had taken only
a few steps forward,
when Rose attacked her
from the front.
Oh!
The question no one seems
to be asking is "how?"
I've been asking
that question.
A-a-a-and right you are to ask,
My Diamond!
B-because, at the time
that Pink was shattered,
Rose Quartz had been
a recognized threat
for several hundred years.
There were no Rose Quartz
soldiers in her entourage,
and none in her guard.
So how did a Rose Quartz,
with no business being
anywhere near Pink Diamond,
get so close in the first place?
Where were Pink Diamond's
attendants?
Her Agates, her Sapphires?
And where was her Pearl?
They were with her,
of course.
They saw the whole thing!
But none of them saw
Rose Quartz approach?
Wouldn't her Sapphires
have seen Rose Quartz coming?
Wouldn't her Agates
have tried to fight her off?
That is strange!
She must have slipped past them!
Even if she did,
wouldn't her Pearl have
cried out in alarm,
"Watch out, my Diamond!"
No, whoever did this was
already close to Pink Diamond,
someone her guards
would allow to get near her,
someone she would listen to
when asked to stop her palanquin
and step outside,
and someone with the authority
to cover it up afterwards!
Someone with supreme authority!
Someone ... like one of you!
Uh, disregard that last statement!
I might have gotten carried away.
Case closed, right, My Diamond?
Yellow, stop it!
Why are you doing this?!
This is our chance!
We gotta go!
- Where?!
- We don't need
- to listen to this nonsense!
- There!
Let's shatter Rose Quartz
and be done with it!
Can't you restrain yourself?!
- But this is pointless!
- No, it's not!
Hurry up
and drive this thing!
Those giant crazy chicks aren't
gonna be distracted forever!
Where is this?
Homeworld.
You think
you can get away, Rose?
You stood your ground on that
little speck called Earth ...
but you're on our world now.
- Addic7ed.com -